Guide to the Sara and Gerald Murphy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Sara and Gerald Murphy papers
1854-2005
YCAL MSS 468
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
72.3
(196 boxes) + 21 broadside, 33 cold storage, 1 record album storage, 2 roll
The collection consists of the personal and family papers of Gerald and Sara Murphy, including material created and accumulated by Gerald and Sara, their children Baoth, Patrick, and Honoria, and the Wiborg family. The collection documents the Murphy's unconventional and artistic lifestyle and their role in the American expatriate community in Paris and Antibes, France during the 1920s and early 1930s, as well as their personal connections with artists and writers of the Modernist period. Also found is material relating to Gerald's father, Patrick Francis Murphy, and his stewardship of the leather goods company, Mark Cross.
Murphy, Gerald, 1888-1964
Murphy, Sara
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift and purchased from John Donnelly, Laura Donnelly, and William Donnelly, 2008-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 93-97, 169, 229-230, and 173-198 (audiovisual material) Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 170-171 (clippings): Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 199-204 and 220 (photograph negatives): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Preservation prints for reference use are available in the digital library.
Separated Materials
One exhibition catalogue was removed from the collection to be cataloged independently from the Papers and has a provenance note linking it to the Murphys.
Associated Materials
Mark Cross Company objects are also located at the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
Sara Wiborg Murphy (1883-1975) and Gerald Murphy (1888-1964)
The lives of Gerald Murphy and Sara Wiborg Murphy are described in Everybody Was So Young: Gerald and Sara Murphy, A Lost Generation Love Story (Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1998) by Amanda Vaill and Sara & Gerald (New York: NYT Times Books, 1982) by Honoria Murphy Donnelly. The following is a brief timeline identifying key events in their lives:
1883 November 7: Sara Sherman Wiborg born.
1888 March 26: Gerald Cleary Murphy born.
1912: Gerald Murphy graduates from Yale University.
1915 December 30: Sara and Gerald are married.
1917 December 19: Honoria Adeline Murphy is born.
1917-1918: Gerald Murphy serves in the U.S. military.
1919 May 13: Baoth Wiborg Murphy is born.
1919 September: Gerald Murphy begins his studies at Harvard University in landscape architecture. The Murphys move to Cambridge, Massachusetts.
1920 Summer: Reside at "The Glebe" in Litchfield, Connecticut.
1920 October 18: Patrick Francis Murphy II is born.
1921 June 11: Sail for Europe.
1921 Summer: Visit Croyde Bay, England.
1921 September: Reside in Paris, France. Reside at the Hôtel Beau-Site before moving to rue Greuze in October.
1922 June: Visit Houlgate on the coast of Normandy, France.
1922 October: Reside in Versailles, France at the Hôtel des Reservoirs.
1923 Summer: Visit Antibes, France and stay at the Hôtel du Cap. The Murphys befriend the Picassos. The Murphys and friends throw a "Mad Beach Party."
1923 September: Reside in Versailles, France.
1924 February: Reside in Antibes, France. Visitors include: F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald, Pablo Picasso and family, Donald Ogden Stewart, John and Katy Dos Passos.
1924 April: Reside in Saint-Cloud, France, at 3 rue Gounod.
1924 May: Frederic T. Murphy dies (Gerald Murphy's brother).
1924 June: Reside in Antibes, France.
1924 September: Reside in Saint-Cloud, France.
1925 March: Reside in Antibes, France.
1925 Summer: Move into "Villa America" in Antibes, France. Guests include: Fitzgeralds, MacLeishes, Rudolph Valentino, Dos Passos, and Stewart.
1928-1929: Reside in California.
1929 May: Reside in Antibes, France.
1929 October: Reside in Montana-Vermala, Switzerland.
1931 Summer: Reside in Bad Aussee, Austria.
1932 January: Reside in Antibes, France.
1932 Summer-1934: Reside in New York City and "Hook Pond," East Hampton, New York.
1934 Summer: Visit Europe.
1934 December: Gerald Murphy becomes President of the Mark Cross Company.
1935 March 17: Baoth Wiborg Murphy dies of meningitis.
1935 Summer-1937: Reside in Saranac Lake, New York.
1937 January 30: Patrick Francis Murphy II dies of tuberculosis.
1937 Summer: Visit Europe. Trip with Alice Lee Myers.
1938: Reside at "Swan Cove," East Hampton, New York and summer in Europe. Sailing with Dos Passos.
1939: Reside in New York City and East Hampton, New York and spend the summer in Europe.
1949: Reside at "Cheer Hall," Sneden's Landing, New York.
1964 October 17: Gerald Murphy dies.
1975 October 9: Sara Murphy dies.
1998 December 22: Honoria Murphy Donnelly dies.
Murphy Family Tree
Family members who are prominent in the papers appear in boldface.
Timothy Murphy
- Patrick Francis Murphy (1858-1931) m. Anna Elizabeth Ryan (circa 1858-1932)
- - 2 Frederic Timothy Murphy (1885-1924) m. Noël Haskins (b. 1895)
- - 2 Gerald Cleary Murphy (1888-1964) m. Sara Sherman Wiborg (1883-1975)
- -- 3 Honoria Adeline Murphy Donnelly (1917-1998) m. John Shelton (b. 1919; divorced 1948-1949) m. William M. Donnelly (1916-1988)
- - - - 4 John Charles Baoth Donnelly (1951-)
- - - - 4 William Sherman Donnelly (1953-)
- - - - 4 Laura Sara Donnelly (1954-)
- - - 3 Baoth Wiborg Murphy (1919-1935)
- - - 3 Patrick Francis Murphy (1920-1937)
- - 2 Esther Murphy (1898-1962) m. John Strachey (1901-1963; divorced 1933) m. Chester A. Arthur III (divorced)
Wiborg Family Tree
Henry Paulinus Wiborg (1821-1867) m. Susan Isidora Bestow (1832-1876)
- 2 Frank Bestow Wiborg (1855-1930) m. Adeline Moulton Sherman (1859-1917)
- - 3 Sara Sherman Wiborg (1883-1975) m. Gerald Cleary Murphy (1888-1964)
- - 3 Mary Hoyt Wiborg (1887-1964)
- - 3 Olga Marie Wiborg (1889-1937) m. Sidney Webster Fish (1885-1950)
- - - 4 Stuyvesant Fish (1926-2003) m. Virginia Small
- 2 Harry Bestow Wiborg (b. 1857)
Sherman Family Tree
Charles Robert Sherman (1790-1829) m. Mary Hoyt (d. 1852)
- 2 Charles Taylor Sherman (1811-1879) m. Elizabeth Williams
- - 3 Mary Hoyt Sherman m. Nelson A. Miles (1839-1925)
- - 3 Henry Stoddard Sherman
- - 3 John J. Sherman
- - 3 Charles F. Cook Sherman
- - 3 Anna Wallace Sherman
- - 3 Eliza A. Williams Sherman m. Colgate Hoyt
- - 3 Elizabeth Bancroft Sherman m. James D. Cameron
- 2 James Sherman
- 2 William Tecumseh Sherman (1820-1891) m. Ellen Boyle Ewing
- - 3 William Ewing Sherman
- - 3 Thomas Ewing Sherman
- - 3 Charley Sherman
- - 3 Philemon Tecumseh Sherman
- - 3 Maria Ewing Sherman
- - 3 Mary Elizabeth Sherman
- - 3 Eleanor Mary Sherman
- - 3 Rachel Sherman
- 2 Lampson P. Sherman
- 2 John Sherman (1823-1900) m. Margaret Cecilia Stewart
- - 3 Adopted daughter
- 2 Hoyt Sherman (1827-1904) m. Sara Elvira Moulton
- - 3 Adeline Moulton Sherman (1859-1917) m. Frank Bestow Wiborg (1855-1930)
- - 3 Frank Allen Sherman (1856-1902) m. Ada Louise Bacon
- - - 4 Sara Moulton Sherman (1888-1969) m. William Ledyard Mitchell (1881-1964)
- - 3 Helen Sherman (1873-1961) m. William Griffith
- 2 Mary Elizabeth Sherman m. William J. Reese
- 2 Fanny Sherman (b. 1829)
- 2 Amelia Sherman m. Robert McComb
Scope and Contents
The Sara and Gerald Murphy Papers are comprised of correspondence, diaries, photographs, objects, artwork, audiovisual material, and printed material documenting the lives of the Murphy family and their circle of friends. The Papers also provide insight into Gerald Murphy's career as a painter. The Murphys' lifestyle is richly documented in photographs and various artifacts, which constitute an array of material culture. The Murphy Papers are a window into the American expatriate community in France during the 1920s, the creation of modern art, and the everyday life of a socially and artistically prominent family. The papers document the Murphys' friendships with a number of prominent authors and artists, including Ellen and Philip Barry, Katherine and John Dos Passos, Zelda and F. Scott Fitzgerald, Ernest Hemingway, Fernand Léger, Ada and Archibald MacLeish, Dorothy Parker, Pablo Picasso, Cole Porter, and Monty Woolley. The Papers also provide evidence of the Murphys' ancestors and their business ventures, including Patrick Murphy and the Mark Cross Company and Frank Wiborg and the Ault and Wiborg Company. The Papers document industry (printing inks and leather goods) during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.
The Murphys' upbringing, education, early travels, and courtship are documented in diaries, notebooks, and photographs. Sara Murphy's diaries, particularly those from 1898 to 1915, provide insight into her life as a young adult and her training in art. Her father, Frank Wiborg, kept detailed diaries that also give a sense of Sara Murphy's childhood and adolescence. Photograph albums record the family's travels, and provide rich insight into the Wiborgs' milieu as well as travel, photography, and customs at the turn of the nineteenth century. Diaries and photographs of Gerald Murphy during his adolescence, while attending Phillips Academy Andover and Yale University, are present in the Papers, although to a lesser degree.
The Murphys' everyday life, style, and circle of friends are documented throughout the Papers. Recognized for infusing the quotidian with creative flair, the Murphys' stylistic choices are represented by photographs and objects, which range from barware to costume jewellery to Mark Cross Company leather goods. Photographs of the Murphys' homes in the United States, France, and Switzerland, recipes in the Personal Papers series, and household goods located in the Objects Series provide insight into the Murphys' decorative tastes and talent for entertaining.
The Murphys' relationships are reflected in correspondence, photographs, and home movies, which illustrate expatriate life in France during the 1920s and the fate of the friendships over time. Fernand Léger is photographed visiting the Murphy family in Switzerland and the United States, and his collage postcards suggest his playful and intimate bond with the Murphys. The Murphys' correspondence and other documents provide evidence of their role as muses to their friends, for example, they were portrayed in F. Scott Fitzgerald's Tender is the Night, Archibald MacLeish's J.B., and Ernest Hemingway's A Moveable Feast. Honoria Murphy Donnelly's diaries and notebooks date from her childhood and adolescence and provide a child's perspective of the Murphy family, including their frequent travels and circle of friends.
Both Sara and Gerald Murphy received artistic training and Gerald Murphy seriously applied himself in becoming a painter while living in France during the 1920s. Examples of Sara Murphy's artwork can be found in the Artwork series as well as tucked into the pages of her father's diaries, located in the Wiborg Family Papers series. Documents pertaining to Gerald Murphy's work as a painter can be found in the Artwork Series. Gerald Murphy's brother, Frederic Murphy, in correspondence with their mother describes visiting Gerald in his studio and provides a unique contemporary (and familial) perspective on his artwork. Material relating to the revived interest in Gerald Murphy's paintings beginning in the 1960s can be found in the Honoria Murphy Donnelly Papers Series.
The Papers also chronicle Gerald Murphy's careers in the military and with the Mark Cross Company. Gerald Murphy's experience studying landscape architecture at Harvard University is documented in his notes and sketches found in the Personal Papers series. His work to revive the Mark Cross Company can be found in the Objects series, which contains various Mark Cross handbags, some of which were designed by Gerald Murphy and are stamped with patent numbers.
The efforts of Gerald Murphy's father, Patrick Murphy, to transform the Mark Cross Company into a successful business specializing in luxury leather goods are documented in his papers, which include notes regarding advertising and merchandising, dating from the early twentieth century. Combined with the Murphys' collection of Mark Cross products, Patrick Murphy's papers represent various aspects of the Mark Cross Company's history.
Several documents pertaining to Gerald Murphy's brother Frederic Murphy (1885-1924) and sister-in-law Noël Haskins (b. 1895) are also present in the Papers. Frederic Murphy's service with the Tank Corps during World War I is documented in several series. These items give insight into American involvement in World War I as well as the perspective of an American soldier from training to deployment to post-war injuries. Frederic and Noël Haskins Murphy's lives in France following World War I are also represented in correspondence and photographs (located in the Photograph series).
Papers relating to Frank Wiborg, Sara Murphy's father, document his work as a partner in the ink manufacturers Ault and Wiborg Company. Frank Wiborg's diaries date from 1873 to 1914 and are a window into his rise as a businessman and the concurrent social and political status of the Wiborg family. The diaries are a record of a prominent industrialist family, who had homes in Cincinnati, New York City, and East Hampton, Long Island, and who were engaged in a number of civic organizations. In his diaries Wiborg provides insight into the daily affairs of the Ault and Wiborg Company and by extension the history of the ink manufacturing industry at the turn of the nineteenth century. Copies of posters for the company and Wiborg's treatise Printing Ink: A History with a Treatise on Modern Methods of Manufacture and Use also document the business.
Honoria Murphy Donnelly's work as an adult to recall, interpret, and preserve memories of her parents and her upbringing is illustrated in her correspondence, publishing projects, and collection of clippings. For example, Donnelly's book Sara & Gerald provides insight into her parents and family life. During research Donnelly interviewed a number of friends and family members, such as Hester Pickman and Noël Haskins Murphy, recordings of which are located in the audiovisual material series. Donnelly's work with a number of researchers interested in her parents and their circle of friends is demonstrated in her correspondence, collection of clippings, and audiovisual material. Donnelly's collection of writings by others based on the Murphys' lives illustrates the Murphys' enduring inspiration and fascination.
Arrangement
Organized into ten series: I. Correspondence, 1911-1980. II. Personal Papers, 1884-1962. III. Photographs, 1880-1990s. IV. Artwork, 1897-1928. V. Objects, 1915-1967. VI. Audiovisual Material, 1932-1999. VII. Honoria Murphy Donnelly Papers, 1925-2003. VIII. Patrick Francis & Anna Elizabeth Ryan Murphy Papers, 1863-1931. IX. Wiborg Family Papers, 1854-1930. X. Additions Since 2011, 1880s-2005.
American literature -- 20th Century; Americans -- France -- History -- 20th Century; Art, American -- 20th Century; Art, Modern -- 20th Century; Modernism (Art); Modernism (Literature); Painters -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Allen, Jay; Baker, Carlos, 1909-1987; Benchley, Robert, 1889-1945; Bishop, John Peale, 1892-1944; Bombois, Camille, 1883-1970; Brackett, Charles, 1892-1969; Brackett, Elizabeth, 1941-2018; Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1891-1967; Campbell, Patrick, Mrs., 1865-1940; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970; Dos Passos, Katharine, -1947; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940; Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1900-1948; Flanner, Janet, 1892-1978; Gill, Brendan, 1914-1997; Hellman, Lillian, 1905-1984; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Hibben, Sheila, 1888-1964; Lederer, Charles, 1910-1976; Léger, Fernand, 1881-1955; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Meyer, Marcelle; Murphy, Baoth; Murphy, Esther, 1898-1962; Murphy, Gerald, 1888-1964; Murphy, Honoria; Murphy, Patrick, 1858-1931; Murphy, Patrick, 1920-1936; Murphy, Sara; Ober, Harold, 1881-1959; O'Hara, John, 1905-1970; Parker, Dorothy, 1893-1967; Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts), 1884-1947; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964; Potter, Jeffrey, 1918-2012; Powell, Dawn, 1897-1965; Roueché, Berton, 1911-1994; Scribner, Charles, 1854-1930; Seldes, Gilbert, 1893-1970; Short, Bobby; Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1894-1980; Turnbull, Andrew, 1921-1970; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972; Woollcott, Alexander, 1887-1943; Woolley, Monty, 1888-1963; Viborg family; Mark Cross
- Correspondence, 1911-1980; Series I; 3.75 linear feet (9 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of the correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  The series documents Sara and Gerald Murphy's personal relationships, most notably with several prominent writers and artists, including John and Katharine Dos Passos, F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald, Ernest Hemingway, Fernand Léger, Pauline Pfeiffer, Dorothy Parker, Ada and Archibald MacLeish, and Cole Porter. While many of these friendships began while the Murphys were expatriates living in France during the 1920s, most of the correspondence dates from a later period, when the Murphys returned to the United States.
  The correspondence attests to the deep affection between the Murphys and their friends, who sought their company and provided support after the death of the Murphys' sons Baoth and Patrick. In turn, the Murphys were dedicated friends. For example, their correspondence documents that the Murphys lent money to F. Scott Fitzgerald, so his daughter, "Scottie," could continue her studies at Vassar and to Fernand Léger so he could attend the openings of his shows in the United States. The MacLeishs' daughter wore Sara Murphy's wedding dress at her marriage ceremony and the Murphys were godparents to Dos Passos's daughter. The Murphys' role as creative inspirations to their friends is also evidenced by their correspondence. For example, Fitzgerald famously drew on Sara and Gerald in his novel Tender Is the Night, which he discusses with Sara in a letter dated August 15, 1935. Archibald MacLeish, who borrowed from the Murphys' lives in his play J. B., sent the Murphys a copy of his sermon on the Book of Job (1955) which predates his artistic piece on this theme.
  In their letters, postcards, and telegrams, the Murphys' friends provide a window into their own personal and creative lives. Ernest Hemingway discusses various hunting and fishing expeditions as well as his writing projects and creative routine. Dawn Powell interweaves narratives of her everyday exploits with descriptions of various writing assignments. Many of the Murphys' correspondents also discuss mutual friends, which similarly illuminates periods in their friends' lives, including illness, the loss of loved ones, divorces, as well as marriages and births. On occasion the letters themselves are creative pieces, such as Léger's humorously crafted postcard collages, Dorothy Parker's notes with clippings of bizarre lines from local newspapers, and Dos Passos' pseudo-military briefing sent to Sara during World War II.
  The Murphys' correspondence with their employees, such as nannies (Henriette Géron, Ernestine Leray) and personal assistant (Vladimir Orloff), gives a sense of the Murphys' movements and activities. Sara and Gerald Murphy gathered around them an extensive group of friends, and while not all of them were artists or went on to portray the Murphys in artistic pursuits, these relationships provide insight into the magnetism of the Murphys.
  - "A" general, 1919, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "B" general, 1919-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Baker, Carlos, 1964 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bank of America, 1929 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barns, Dixon, 1955, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barry, Philip and Ellen, 1937-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Benchley, Robert, 1935-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bishop, John Peale, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bissill, Maria, 1946 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bolton, Frances, 1937, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bombois, Camille, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brackett, Charles and Elizabeth, 1935, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brennan, Fanny, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Breval, Ivan, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Brooke, Gina and Alex, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1940 August (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Burton, Spence, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "C" general, 1918-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Calé, Katha, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick, 1926-1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1963 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cheney, Frankie, 1963-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cobb, Carolyn, 1947 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Connolly, Marc, 1945 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cornell, Katharine, 1961 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cristofanetti, Lucia, 1941-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Curtis, Charlie, 1947 September, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "D" general, 1919-1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Daniel, Frances B., 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Donnelly, Honoria Murphy, 1951 August 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Donohue, Lester, 1937-1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dos Passos, John and Katharine, 1933-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 35-44)
  - Dos Passos, John and Katharine, 1933-1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
  - Dos Passos, John, from Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Dos Passos, Katharine, 1934-1944, undated (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
  - Draper, Ruth and Muriel, 1935 March 30, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "E" general, 1918-1937 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Includes empty film boxes
  - "F" general, 1943, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Faulkner, Barry, 1960 January 8 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott and Zelda, 1935-1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Includes letter from Scottie Fitzgerald Smith
  - Flandrau, Grace, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Flanner, Janet, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "G" general, 1911-1962 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Geŕon, Henriette "Mamzelle", 1935-1946 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Griffith, Mrs. W. O., 1945, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Gugler, Eric and Anne, 1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - "H" general, 1919-1963 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Haberer, Garnet, 1946-1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Harvey, Jason, 1954 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Heller, Harold, 1945-1967 (Box 3, Folder 65-66)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1939-1973 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1926-1945 (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
  - Hemingway, Jack, 1949 October 17 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Hemingway, Mary Welsh, 1965 December 15, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Hemingway, Pauline, 1934-1949, undated (Box 4)
  - Hibben, Sheila, 1950-1962 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Hitchcock, Alfred and Alma, 1951-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Honeycutt, Ann, 1962 February 18, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - "I" general, 1919 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - "J" general, 1934-1960 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - James, William and Alice, 1938-1959 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - "K" general, 1948, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - King, Muriel, 1937-1952 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - "L" general, 1919-1964 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Lassen, Suzanne, 1951 June 24, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Lederer, Charles, 1940, 1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1930-1965 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1930-1965 (Box 5, Folder 86-87)
    Includes postcards with collage
  - Leray, Ernestine, 1926-1959 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Lewis, Lefty, 1943-1963 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Lindsay, Elizabeth, 1936-1949 (Box 5, Folder 90)